<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-05-07T16:27:07-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Oscar Yih</title><subtitle>Ruby on Rails Developer in SoCal</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Difference between HTML, CSS and JavaScript</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/HTML-CSS-JavaScript/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Difference between HTML, CSS and JavaScript" /><published>2017-05-07T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2017-05-07T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/HTML-CSS-JavaScript</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/HTML-CSS-JavaScript/">&lt;p&gt;A friend asked me what the difference between HTML, CSS and JavaScript and if you could only have HTML and CSS, which would you choose?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I had to put these languages in layman terms, I would use the description of a human being.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;HTML would be skeleton structure&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CSS would be the skin, clothes and makeup&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JavaScript would be the brains and the muscles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;html&quot;&gt;HTML&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I describe HTML as a skeleton because it is the base structure of a web page that every page needs, because without a skeleton a human being would just be a digusting pile of mess. 
Alternatively, HTML by itself without the effects of CSS would just be a pile of bones which is equally as unattractive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/without_css.png&quot; alt=&quot;without_css.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, I removed the CSS file for this page and took a screenshot to showcase what it would look like in pure unadulterated HTML and it’s not pretty. To be fair, my CSS file on my blog only really centers the elements in HTML among a few other things but on another website with more extensive CSS the difference would be even more drastic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;css&quot;&gt;CSS&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I describe CSS as aesthetics because its purpose is to instruct HTML where to place its text and how to display it. Without CSS, HTML would place all its text and images starting from left to right as shown previously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the human metaphor, imagine a pair of eyes just randomly placed from left to right as designed by HTML like some kind of Picasso painting. While the role of HTML is to just display a pair of eyes, it’s the role of CSS to tell HTML where to place a pair of eyes, in the center of the head, spaced slightly apart and right above the nose, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;JavaScript&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While HTML and CSS are static languages, meaning they just sit there and try to look pretty, JavaScript is a dynamic and more like a true programming language with logic and functions.*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JavaScript has functions which can make a web page more interactive, which ties in with my metaphor of JavaScript being the muscles. But what are muscles without a brain? A human being would be a disaster if there was no brain to control its muscles and thereby its actions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like humans don’t normally flail their arms and legs around wildly, JavaScript makes sure actions are contained and called when they need to be called. Such examples include displaying certain elements or hiding them when clicking on a button or hovering over an element.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Those that knew CSS very well are able to make animations like JavaScript&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;html-or-css-which-one-is-more-important&quot;&gt;HTML or CSS, which one is more important?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve read through the previous paragraphs, you’d have a better idea of HTML and CSS and can probably already figure out my answer. HTML and CSS go hand in hand. HTML without CSS is just text on a screen and if CSS had no HTML then all you would see is a blank screen. If I were forced to pick only one, HTML would be my choice but a world with only HTML is truly a world of nightmares.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">A friend asked me what the difference between HTML, CSS and JavaScript and if you could only have HTML and CSS, which would you choose?</summary></entry></feed>